A Guide to the Papers of John Randolph of Roanoke, 1781-1860, [n.d.]
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series I: Letters and Documents
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1816 June 23., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed; postmark illegible. #3677. (Box-folder 5:20)
  - John Randolph to Richard Bland Lee, 1816 August 20, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed; Richmond VA, August 2. #6489. (Box-folder 5:21)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1816 October 27., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed; postmark illegible. #3677. (Box-folder 5:22)
    Mentions "hear[ing] occasionally from Frank Key."
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1816 December 29., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. #3677. (Box-folder 5:23)
  - [Rufus?] King to John Randolph 1817 January 28, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. #5718-e. (Box-folder 5:23A)
    Accepts an invitation for the next day.
  - Jose Francisco Correa da Serra to John Randolph 1817 February 10, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. #5718-e. (Box-folder 5:23B)
    Informs Randolph that he has no information about Mr. Gilmer but expects Mr. Walsh in a few days. He also tells him not be uneasy about the pamphlet because it finally came to Mr. Walsh through Mr. Hopkinson and is now in Baltimore ready to be published if not already published in Philadelphia.
  - John Randolph to H[armanus] Bleecker, 1817 February 20., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with separate address leaf, with wax seal; docketed; postmarked Georgetown, February 22. #3677. (Box-folder 5:24)
    In a postscript, Randolph instructs Bleecker that "apropos as you are the only person I ever knew to bear this Christian name why not write it out at full length."
  - John Randolph to Joseph A. Clay, 1817 February 22, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; postmarked Georgetown, February 2[3]? #6015. (Box-folder 5:25)
  - John Randolph to Henry Middleton Rutledge, 1817 February 22, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed. #8283. (Box-folder 5:26)
  - John Randolph to [St. George Tucker], 1817 February 28, ALS, 5 pp. on 3 l.; with partial typed transcript. #3400. (Box-folder 5:27)
  - John Randolph to Francis W[alker] Gilmer, 1817 March 15, ALS, 4 pp.; photostat, location of original unknown. #3553-b. (Box-folder 5:28)
  - John Randolph to Edward Booker, 1817 April 2, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; silked; postmarked Richmond VA, April 2. #2656-a. (Box-folder 5:29)
  - John Randolph to [John Morton], 1817 April 23, ALS, fragment, 1 p. #2932-a. (Box-folder 5:30)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1817 July 20., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. #3677. (Box-folder 5:31)
  - John Randolph to [Henry Middleton Rutledge], 1817 August 2, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. #6693. (Box-folder 5:32)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1817 October 3, ALS, 6 pp. on 4 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:33)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1817 October 12, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:34)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1817 November 5, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:35)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1817 November 24., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed. #3677. (Box-folder 5:36)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1818 January 5-6., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. #3677. (Box-folder 5:37)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer Garnett], 1818 January 20, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:38)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1818 March 16., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed. #3677. (Box-folder 5:39)
    Mentions "Frank Key['s]" operation for a fistula, and mentions reading Shakespeare, Milton, Cowper, and Coleridge.
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1818 July 7, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:40)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to James Mercer Garnett, 1818 July 13, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Richmond VA, July [?]. #1883. (Box-folder 5:41)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1818 July 15., ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed; postmarked [Roanoke VA], July 21. #3677. (Box-folder 5:42)
    Mentions his eclectic reading.
  - John Randolph to Francis Walker Gilmer, 1818 July--1826 January 17, ALSs, 57 pp. on 57 l.; copies in unidentified hand. #3400. (Box-folder 5:43)
    1818 July; 1820 July 1; 1820 December 24; 1821 January 12; 1821 December 27; 1821 July 22; 1822 February [2]6; 1824 January 26; 1824 February 21; 1824 March 9; 1824 March 13; 1824 November 8; 1824 December 11; 1825 February 2; 1825 Ash Wednesday [February 16] 1825 February 25; 1825 March 1; 1825 March 6; 1825 March 31; 1825 July 2; 1825 July 26; 1826 January 8; 1826 January 12; 1826 January 17; 1826 February 10.
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1818 August 1, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; #1883. (Box-folder 5:44)
  - Inscription, John Randolph to Joseph Bryan, 1818 August 8, AL, copies, 3 pp. on 2 l. Two copies of this inscription, one not dated, and the other dated 1888 January 5; Prayer Book with original inscription cat. as BX5943.A1 1810c. #3400-a. (Box-folder 5:45)
  - John Randolph to Henry Carrington 1818 August 13, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. #5718-e (Box-folder 5:45A)
    Says that he could write a letter of advice along the lines of a popular pamphlet of some time ago, entitled Letter from an old politician to a young prince but it would be unnecessary since he already has Edmund Burke. Instead he will send a paper on The motives of France in aiding us in our contest for Independency against the mother country. Randolph also asks two favors of his young friend, that he take back the mule and agree to dine with him and a relative of Colonel Taylor of Caroline.
  - John Randolph to Henry Carrington, 1818 August 14, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with three newspaper clippings, one calling card, and one bookplate. #8716-b. (Box-folder 5:46)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1818 September 30, ALS, 6 pp. on 4 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:47)
  - [John Randolph] to [Harmanus] Bleecker, 1818 October 10., AL, fragment, 4 pp. on 1 l. #3677. (Box-folder 5:48)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1818 October 10, AL, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf, with partially obscured wax seal; 19th century copy addressed to Miss Davenport in unidentified hand. #6686. (Box-folder 5:49)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1818 October 24, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:50)
  - John Randolph to J[ohn] R[andolph] Bryan and "Master Clay," 1818 November 5, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. Letter brittle and discolored. #3400. (Box-folder 5:51)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1818 November 16., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal. #3677. (Box-folder 5:52)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1818 November 16, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; #1883. (Box-folder 5:53)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1818 December 15, ALS, 5 pp. on 3 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:54)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1818 December 22, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; #1883. (Box-folder 5:55)
  - 1818 John Randolph to [Henry?] Carrington 1818, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. #5718-e (Box-folder 5:55A)
    Regrets that he will unexpectedly not be at home as planned, because he must "honor the memory of old Ambrose Owen, who has labored honestly for three score years and ten in an age & country where avarice, rapacity & idleness lead to any mode of self-support or amassing a fortune except honest industry."
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, [n.d.] [c.a. 1818-1829]?, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:56)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1819 March 25., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with separate address leaf, with wax seal; docketed. #3677. (Box-folder 5:57)
  - John Randolph to Charles Fenton Mercer, 1819 March 25, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #7224. (Box-folder 5:58)
  - D[elia Forman] Bryan to John Randolph, 1819 April 23, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Savannah GA, April 26. #3400. (Box-folder 5:59)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1819 May 22., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed; postmarked Albany NY, May 31. #3677. (Box-folder 5:60)
  - John R[andolph] Bryan to [John Randolph], 1819 September 20, ALS, 1 p. #3400. (Box-folder 5:61)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1819 November 3, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:62)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1819 November 8, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:63)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to J[ohn] R[andolph] B[ryan] and E. T[udor] B[ryan], 1819 November 20, ALS, 1 p.; 19th century? copy in unidentified hand. #2118. (Box-folder 5:64)
  - D[elia Forman] Bryan to John Randolph, 1819 December 6, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Savannah GA, December 16. #3400. (Box-folder 5:65)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1819 December 17., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with separate address leaf, with wax seal; docketed. #3677. (Box-folder 5:66)
  - John Randolph to Charles L. Carter, 1819 December 17, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; mylar. #9708. (Box-folder 5:67)
  - [John Randolph] to Mr. Skinner, 1819 December 29, AL, 1 p. With signature of T[homas] M[ann] Randolph glued to the letter. Folder contains a note concerning a collector's confusion of the Randolph's and the pasting of this signature to the letter. #6435. (Box-folder 5:68)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1820 January 1., ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3677. (Box-folder 5:69)
  - James Mercer Garnett to John Randolph, 1820 January 3, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed; #1883. (Box-folder 5;70)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1820 January 11, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:71)
  - John Randolph to Edward J. Coale, 1820 January 13, ALS, 1 p. #6489. (Box-folder 5:72)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1820 January 22., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. #3677. (Box-folder 5:73)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1820 January 24, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; #1883. (Box-folder 5:74)
  - [James Mercer Garnett] to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1820 January 28, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:75)
    Signed "Your old friend, Cornplanter," concerning tobacco planting.
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to James Mercer Garnett, 1820 January 29, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. #1883. (Box-folder 5:76)
  - Thomas M[arsh] F[orman] Bryan to John Randolph, 1820 January 30, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with detached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 5:77)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1820 February 7, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:78)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1820 February 9, ALS, 6 pp. on 4 l.; with address leaf; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:79)
  - John Randolph to Joseph Clay, 1820 February 20, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. Brittle along old folds. #8477. (Box-folder 5:80)
  - [John Randolph] to [James Mercer Garnett], 1820 February 20, AL, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:81)
    Addressed to "Cornplanter," concerning growing tobacco.
  - James Mercer Garnett to John Randolph, 1820 February 22, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:82)
  - John Randolph to [John Brockenbrough], 1820 February 23, AL, copy, 3 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:83)
    A copy of a letter from Randolph to Brockenbrough presumably sent to James Mercer Garnett ("cornplanter"), with annotations possibly in Randolph's hand.
  - J[ohn] Randolph Bryan to John Randolph, 1820 February 28, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. #3400. (Box-folder 5:84)
  - J[ohn] Randolph Bryan to John Randolph, 1820 February 28, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. Possibly draft form of letter in preceding entry; torn and brittle; placed in mylar sleeve. #3400. (Box-folder 5:85)
  - W. W. Seaton to John Randolph, 1820 February (Friday), ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:86)
  - John Randolph to [John] Randolph [Bryan], 1820 March 1, ALS, 1 p. #3400. (Box-folder 5:87)
  - Speech by John Randolph with autograph corrections by Thomas Jefferson, 1820 March 3, AMS, 6 pp. on 6 l.; photocopy; Original in Thomas Jefferson papers. #3620. (Box-folder 5:88)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1820 March 11., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed. #3677. (Box-folder 5:89)
  - J[ohn] Randolph Bryan to [John Randolph], 1820 March 13, ALS, 1 p.; photostat only. #2118. (Box-folder 5:90)
    With John Randolph's instructions to John Randolph Bryan concerning spelling and grammatical mistakes.
  - D[elia Forman] Bryan to John Randolph, 1820 March 19, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Savannah GA, March 21. #3400. (Box-folder 5:91)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1820 March 22, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:92)
  - John Randolph to John Wickham, 1820 March 24, ALS, 1 p.; incomplete, final page only. #15753. (Box-folder 5:92a)
  - J[ohn] Randolph Bryan to John Randolph, 1820 March 26, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. #3400. (Box-folder 5:93)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1820 March 31, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:94)
  - John Randolph to John Wickham, 1820 April 1, AL, signature excised. #15753. (Box-folder 5:94a)
  - D[elia Forman] Bryan to John Randolph, 1820 April 22, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Savannah GA, April 26 and again Richmond VA, May 1. #3400. (Box-folder 5:95)
  - John Randolph to John Randolph Bryan and Thomas Marsh Forman Bryan, 1820 May 30, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with typescript copy. #3400. (Box-folder 5:96)
  - John Randolph to John Randolph Bryan and Thomas M[arsh] Forman Bryan, 1820 June 13, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; with typescript copy. Extremely brittle along old folds, and letter discolored. #3400. (Box-folder 5:97)
  - John Randolph to Henry Middleton Rutledge, 1820 June 19, ALS, 1 p. Partially mounted, glued at the top to a backing. #6489. (Box-folder 5:98)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer Garnett], 1820 July 3, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:99)
    Addressed at bottom of letter to "Cornplanter."
  - Thomas [Marsh] F[orman] Bryan to John Randolph, 1820 July 4, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Savannah GA, July 6. #3400. (Box-folder 5:100)
  - John Randolph to Henry Lee, 1820 December 21, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. Left edge of letter glued to acidic fragment, resulting in discoloration and deterioration along the left hand margin. #4603. (Box-folder 5:101)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1821 January 30., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with separate address leaf, with wax seal; docketed. #3677. (Box-folder 5:102)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1821 February 10, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:103)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1821 February 22, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:104)
  - J[ohn] B[rockenbrough] to John Randolph, 1821 March 2, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Richmond VA, March 2. #4152. (Box-folder 5:105)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1821 April 9, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:106)
  - John Randolph to Unidentified, 1821 April 13, ANS, 1 p. #2832-a. (Box-folder 5:107)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1821 May 17., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed. #3677. (Box-folder 5:108)
  - J[ohn] Randolph Bryan to John Randolph, 1821 May 19, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Savannah GA, May 19, and Atlanta GA, May 22. #3400. (Box-folder 5:109)
  - John Randolph to Walter Coles, 1821 June 11, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed. #5076. (Box-folder 5:110)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1821 June 12, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:111)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer Garnett], 1821 June 18, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:112)
  - James Mercer Garnett to John Randolph, 1821 August 12, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; wax seal; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:113)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer Garnett], 1821 August 21, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:114)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1821 December 29., ALS, 1 p.; with separate address leaf, with wax seal; docketed. #3677. (Box-folder 5:115)
  - John Randolph to J[ames] M[ercer] G[arnett], 1822 January 9, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:116)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer Garnett], 1822 January 26, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:117)
    Addressed to "Cornplanter."
  - John Randolph to Samuel T. Anderson, 1822 February 7, ALS, 1 p.; photostat only. #4365-a. (Box-folder 5:118)
  - Notes "Copied from Col. [Thomas Hart] Benton's M.S." by John Randolph, 1822 March 8, AMsS, 5 pp. on 3 l.; Barrow. #3339. (Box-folder 5:119)
  - John Randolph to Gen. Theodorus Bailey, 1822 March 16, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed. #9371. (Box-folder 5:120)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1822 May 21, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:121)
  - Maria Edgeworth to John Randolph 1822 June 13, ALS, 4 p. on 1 l. with attached address leaf. #5718-e (Box-folder 5:121A)
    Reminds Randolph of his promise to send her an American poem which was in the style of Lord Byron, and arranges to give him a copy of the memoirs of her father, Richard Edgeworth, which she had recently completed. She also asks him to visit her at Edgeworth's Town, if he should ever visit Ireland. Note on address leaf says "I seal with the rose, thistle & shamrock--What is the American emblem? Or is there one?"
  - John Randolph, 1822 June 19, AMs, 1 p. With a note on the verso mentioning the date and location of the entry. #3400. (Box-folder 5:122)
  - Elizabeth Fry to John Randolph 1822 June 26, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. #5718-e. (Box-folder 5:122A)
    Inviting him to Plashet House, Essex, England, with Randolph's note on the back describing his visit there.
  - John Randolph to Jacob Harvey, 1822 September 30, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf on verso; postmarked [America?], 1822 Oct. 12. Address leaf pasted to verso of letter. #8347. (Box-folder 5:123)
  - J[ohn] Randolph Bryan to John [Randolph], 1822 December 15, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached partial address leaf; docketed. #2118. (Box-folder 5:124)
  - John Randolph to J[ames] M[ercer] G[arnett], 1822 December 31, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:125)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer Garnett], 1822 "Babel Good Friday", AL, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 5:126)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1823 January 2, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; Barrow; postmarked Fredricksburg VA, January 8; docketed. #1883. (Box-folder 6:1)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1823 February 10, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:2)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1823 July 6, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:3)
  - James Mercer Garnett to John Randolph, 1823 August 18, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:4)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1823 September 10, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:5)
  - James Mercer Garnett to John Randolph, 1823 September 20, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed; Barrow; postmarked Fredericksburg VA, September 2[6]? #1883. (Box-folder 6:6)
  - John Randolph to John Rodgers, 1823 September 20, ALS, 1 p. #3440-a. (Box-folder 6:7)
    Letter to the "First Commander of the Navy" by Randolph on behalf of John Randolph Bryan to "enter...the Navy as a midshipman."
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1823 September 26, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:8)
  - John Randolph to Thomas M[arsh] Forman Bryan, 1823 October 11, ALS, 1 p.; with address on verso; docketed. Brittle along old folds, and upper third of letter entirely detached. #10050. (Box-folder 6:9)
  - John Randolph to John Randolph Bryan, 1823 October 18, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached partial address leaf. Letter brittle along folds, and bottom eighth of letter detached, but held together with tape. #3400. (Box-folder 6:10)
  - James Mercer Garnett to John Randolph, 1823 October 21, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; Barrow; postmarked Fredericksburg VA, October 23. #1883. (Box-folder 6:11)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1823 November 1, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:12)
  - John Randolph to [John] Randolph [Bryan], 1823 November 22, ALS, 1 p. #3400. (Box-folder 6:13)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1823 December 11, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:14)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1823 December 22, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:15)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1823 December 26, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:16)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1824 January 1, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:17)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1824 January 8, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:18)
  - John Randolph to William Brent, Jr., 1824 January 8, ALS, 1 p. #2529. (Box-folder 6:18A)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1824 January 10, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:19)
  - John Randolph to J[ames] M[ercer] G[arnett], 1824 January 12, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:20)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1824 January 14, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:21)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1824 January 15, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:22)
  - J[ohn] Marshall to John Randolph, 1824 January 17, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Richmond VA, January 17. #3339. (Box-folder 6:23)
    Thanking Randolph for "the report on the Secretary of the Treasury."
  - John Randolph to J[ohn] Randolph Bryan, 1824 January 20, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #2118. (Box-folder 6:24)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1824 January 27, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:25)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1824 February 9, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:26)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1824 February 12, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:27)
  - J[ohn] B[rockenbrough] to John Randolph, 1824 February 18, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Richmond VA, February 18. #3339. (Box-folder 6:28)
  - John Randolph to Jacob Harvey, 1824 March 1, ALS, 1 p. #3920. (Box-folder 6:29)
  - Henry St. George Tucker to John Randolph, 1824 March 20, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Winchester VA, March 22. #2118. (Box-folder 6:30)
  - John Randolph to J[ames] M[ercer] G[arnett], 1824 April 5, ANS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:31)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1824 April 10, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:32)
  - James Mercer Garnett to Dr. [John] Randolph, 1824 April 20, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. #1883. (Box-folder 6:33)